張凱鵬 (ZHANG, KAIPENG)

Tel: (86) 18817957729

E-mail: kp_zhang@foxmail.com

Homepage: http://kpzhang93.github.io/

About Me

I am a researcher at SenseTime. I received my M.S. degree at Graduate Institute of Networking and Multimedia, National Taiwan University in 2018. Before that, I received my B.E. degrees in 2016 from Donghua University. I also did research internship at Microsoft Research Asia, Tencent AI Lab and MMLAB of CUHK at Shenzhen.

My research interest mainly lies in computer vision, deep learning, and face analysis.









Education

National Taiwan University

09/2016 - 08/2018

M.S. in Graduate Institute of Networking and Multimedia, supervised by Prof. Winston Hsu.

GPA: 4.1/4.3

Donghua University, Shanghai

09/2012 - 06/2016

B.Eng. in Computer Network Engineering (Excellent Class)

GPA: 87/100

Experience

SenseTime

09/2018 - Present

Researcher

Large-scale face recognition

Visual Computing Group, Microsoft Research Asia

01/2018 - 07/2018

Research Intern

Mentor: Dr. Dong Chen

Large-scale face recognition

Tencent AI Lab 07/2017 - 09/2017

Research Intern

Mentor: Dr. Zhifeng Li and Dr. Wei Liu

Real-time face detection and alignment

National Taiwan University Master student & Research assistant

09/2016 - 08/2018

Adviser: Prof. Winston Hsu

Low-resolution face hallucination and recognition

Accepted by ECCV 2018

Virtual Try-On Shoe

Accepted by ACCV 2018

Disguised Faces in the Wild

1st winner of Disguised Faces in the Wild Challenge, CVPR 2018.

Attribute Augmented Convolutional Neural Network for Face Hallucination

Accepted by CVPRW 2018

Using two-stream contextual CNN with inside cascaded structure for fast and accurate face detection Accepted by ICCV 2017

Group-level emotion recognition in the wild

1st winner of EmotionW, ICMI 2017 Grand Challenge

2nd winner of EmotionW, ICMI 2018 Grand Challenge

Multimedia Laboratory, Shenzhen Institutes of Advanced Technology

07/2015 - 08/2016

Visiting student

Adviser: Prof. Zhifeng Li and Prof. Yu Qiao

- Face Recognition using proposed discriminative deep feature learning approach.
 Accepted by ECCV 2016
- Joint face detection and alignment using multi-task cascaded convolutional networks
 Accept by IEEE SPL
- Facial gender, smile and accessories classification using deep convolutional neural networks 1st winner of ChaLearn Looking at People Challenge Track 2 & 3, CVPR 2016.

Publications (2 ECCV, 1 ICCV, 3 CVPRW, 1ACCV, 2 ICMI, 1 SPL)

- Kaipeng Zhang, Zhanpeng Zhang, Chia-Wen Cheng, Winston Hsu, Yu Qiao, Wei Liu and Tong Zhang, "Super-Identity Convolutional Neural Network for Face Hallucination", *ECCV*, 2018.
- Kaipeng Zhang, Ya-Liang Chang and Winston Hsu, "Deep Disguised Faces Recognition", CVPRW, 2018.
- Chao-Te Chou, Cheng-Han Lee, **Kaipeng Zhang**, Hu Cheng Lee and Winston Hsu, "Pose Invariant Virtual Try-On Shoe with Conditional Image Completion", *ACCV*, 2018.
- Kai Wang, Xiaoxing Zeng, Jianfei Yang, Debin Meng, Kaipeng Zhang, Xiaojiang Peng and Yu Qiao, "Cascade Attention Networks For Group Emotion Recognition with Face, Body and Image Cues", ICMI Grand Challenge, 2018.
- Cheng-Han Lee, **Kaipeng Zhang**, Hu Cheng Lee, Chia-Wen Cheng and Winston Hsu, "Attribute Augmented Convolutional Neural Network for Face Hallucination", *CVPRW*, 2018.
- Kaipeng Zhang, Zhanpeng Zhang, Hao Wang, Zhifeng Li, Yu Qiao and Wei Liu, "Detecting Faces Using Inside Cascaded Contextual CNN", *ICCV*, 2017.
- Lianzhi Tan, Kaipeng Zhang, Kai Wang, Xiaoxing Zeng, Xiaojiang Peng and Yu Qiao, "Group Emotion Recognition with Individual Facial Emotion CNNs and Global Image Based CNNs", ICMI Grand Challenge, 2017.
- Yandong Wen, Kaipeng Zhang, Zhifeng Li and Yu Qiao, "A Discriminative Deep Feature Learning Approach for Face Recognition", ECCV, 2016.
- Kaipeng Zhang, Zhanpeng Zhang, Zhifeng Li and Yu Qiao, "Joint Face Detection and Alignment using Multi-task Cascaded Convolutional Networks", *IEEE SPL*, vol. 23, no. 10, pp. 1499-1503, 2016.
- Kaipeng Zhang, Lianzhi Tan, Zhifeng Li, Yu Qiao, "Gender and Smile Classification using Deep Convolutional Neural Networks", CVPRW, 2016.

Selected Honors & Awards

| Disguised Faces in the Wild Workshop, CVPR 2018, Ist winner | 2018 |
|--|------|
| Group-level emotion recognition, EmotiW, ICMI 2018 Grand Challenge, 2 nd winner | 2018 |
| Group-level emotion recognition, EmotiW, ICMI 2017 Grand Challenge, Ist winner | 2017 |
| Accessories Classification, ChaLearn Looking at People Challenging, CVPR 2016, Ist winner | 2016 |
| Smile and Gender Classification, ChaLearn Looking at People Challenging, CVPR 2016, 1st winner | 2016 |
| Outstanding Undergraduate Thesis | 2016 |

Academic Service

Reviewer of ACCV 2018, CVPR 2018, TPAMI, TIP, TNNLS, Neurocomputing, and SPL